<Publish>
  <!-- Leave empty for first publish; the toolchain fills it in and you keep it for updates. -->
  <ModId Value="151632" />
  <DisplayName Value="Prison Overflow Manager [Beta]" />
  <ShortDescription Value="Eases prisoner-transport backlogs by scaling prison van capacity during a crime wave." />
  <LongDescription>
# Prison Overflow Manager

Sentenced criminals shouldn't be stuck in police-station holding cells forever because a prison van never shows up. When your city falls behind on transporting prisoners, this mod temporarily gives every prison more van capacity so more vans are dispatched to collect them — then quietly puts it back once the backlog clears.

Unlike blunt "remove crime" mods, the loop stays intact: you still build prisons, vans still drive, criminals still get collected. The mod only helps your existing prisons keep up with a spike.

## Features
- **Soft scaling** (on by default): raises the prison van capacity of every prison while sentenced criminals are piling up at police stations, and restores vanilla capacity once the backlog clears — nobody is released
- **Configurable threshold** — how many criminals waiting for a prison van counts as a backlog
- **Configurable scaled capacity** (100–500% of normal)
- **Early release** (off by default): a last resort for saves where prisoners never get collected (e.g. a city with no prison), with a grace period of 1–30 in-game days
- Live backlog readout and peak-backlog stat to help you pick a threshold
- **Adjustable sweep frequency** (1–64 scans per in-game day)
- Lightweight: scans a few times per in-game day, no per-frame cost

## Notes
- Only prison van capacity is scaled — prisoner holding capacity is left alone, so the "build more prisons" loop stays intact
- Van capacity is always scaled from each prison's true vanilla value, so it never compounds
- If another mod changes a prison's van capacity while scaling is active, this mod leaves that prison alone rather than overwriting it
- Early release frees criminals the same way the game does when a sentence ends — nobody is deleted
- Safe to add or remove from a save at any time; switching the mod off restores vanilla capacity immediately
- Source Code can be found on [GitHub](https://github.com/ryangils/Prison-Overflow-Manager)
  </LongDescription>
  <!-- Add a 1:1 PNG (min 256x256) before publishing. -->
  <Thumbnail Value="Properties/Thumbnail.png" />
  <Tag Value="Code Mod" />
  <ModVersion Value="1.0.0" />
  <GameVersion Value="1.6.*" />
  <ChangeLog>
Initial release.
  </ChangeLog>
  <ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ryangils/Prison-Overflow-Manager" />
</Publish>
